PROJECT MANAGER/OPERATION LEAD/ORACLE ARCHITECT

Professional Summary

IT Manager / Sr. Program Manager / Infrastructure Architect

Multifaceted technical career with 16-year track record of innovation and success Technically sophisticated program/support team management with extensive experience in highly matrixed organizations, working collaboratively with internal and external vendor teams. Proven leadership abilities and project successes, with the ability to deliver requirements on time and on budget under uncertain environment. Eager to leverage skill set and experience on a larger scale. Business Solutions & Improvements / Program Management / Managing & Coaching IT resiliency Architecture design / Troubleshooting & Issue Resolution / Capacity Planning

Core Qualifications

Oracle Database, RAC Cluster, Linux, Unix, Windows OS, LAN, VLAN, WAN, EMC Storage, Oracle engineered systems: Exadata, Exalogic, ZDLRA, PCA, MS Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Visio, Project, Private/Public Cloud infrastructure, Network Design Oracle 11g New Feature ~ Oracle 10g Rac Administration ~ Data Administration/ Upgrade rel 8.44 Ed1 for PeopleSoft ~ Integration Tools/Application Engine for PeopleSoft ~ PeopleTools I / PeopleTools II – Accelerated ~ Oracle 10g New Feature for Administrator ~ Oracle 9i RAC Administration ~ Oracle 9i New Features for Administrator ~ Oracle Designer 2000 ~ Oracle Performance Tuning ~ Data Architect for Data Warehouse

Experience

Project Manager/Operation Lead/Oracle Architect 02/2010 to 02/2013 GENERAL ELECTRIC City, STATE

- Van Buren Twp.
- Successfully led projects in building & supporting of GE resiliency platform for critical ERP systems for GE TRANS, GE Healthcare, GE Aviation, GE Corporate.
- The resiliency platform architecture design includes Exadata, Exalogic, ZDLRA, PCA which are all oracle engineered system.
- Tasks included servers, network switches and storage components with special design to provide special business solution, fast performance to database, application and cloud base environment preparartion.
- Lead the operational team in delivering production support, solution designs, migration success, and architecture design for new projects.
- Ensure the team is able to support a system that is used for GE financial closing, GE treasury to Federal Government reports generation.
- Key Achievements: Architected and Built 41 Engineered systems for GE critical ERPs and Hyperion as ERP Resiliency.
- 14 Exadata, 8 Exalogic, 8 ZDLRA, 4 PCA, 4 ZFS and 3 T5 Exalytics Migrated 12 critical ERPs to Resilient Platform for Trans, Avi, Healthcare, Sourcing, Global research, SOA to reduce P1/P0 issue by 99%.
- Consolidate 40 + EPM Hyperion databases to Exadata to save 20% HW/Maintenance cost for 2017 calendar year.
- Finish POC for CCL on the Platform to guarantee 40% performance improvement.
- Consolidate DB backups on ZDLRA to save 30% backup storage.
- Reduced Engineer system built time by 50%.
- Simplification initiation-- Completed POC of multiple DevOps tools to improve systems manageability to improve operation productivity by 40%.
- Maintaining Relationship with Oracle teams to support Engineered Systems to reduce average issue fix time.
- Cultivated customer relationships resulting in strong confidence in the team's ability to perform.
- Built and lead 24x7 operation support team to manage Engineered Systems to reduce RTS cost for business over oracle managed services by 35%.
- Designed and implemented DR plan on Exa Platform, then successfully executed DR drills for SSS, GRC, and Transportation.
- DR failover time reduced from 8 hours to 2 hours.
- Evaluated, planned, and coordinated with Oracle to execute multi-day patching cycles on Exa platforms with minimal downtime and impact to production.

Sr. Oracle DBA/Data Architect 01/2000 to 01/2010 FLAGSTAR BANK City, STATE

- Governed a complex environment with 40+ databases from 5GB to 2TB in size.
- Led infrastructure design, system implementation, maintenance and user support.
- Maintained databases e.g.
- real-time troubleshooting, performance tuning, database usage proactive monitoring, capacity planning, staging system refreshing, and database support to development teams.
- Key Achievements: Configured and set up Oracle 10g RAC cluster using Raw device and Veritas File system; performed upgrade Oracle 9i RAC database to Oracle 10g RAC.
- Achieved \$2.5M cost saving by replacing high-cost servers with inexpensive server clusters without sacrificing capacity.
- Designed backup and recovery strategy for systems using BCV split, conducted data and structure export to meet various recovery requirements.
- Improved database performance by upgrading Oracle 8i databases to Oracle 9i, 10g.
- Provided 24x7 support for all critical systems.
- Previous role as an Oracle Application DBA at TAC AUTOMOTIVE (1998-2000).

Education

Master of Science (MS): Electrical Computer Engineering Wayne State University City, State Electrical Computer Engineering Bachelor of Science (BS): Chemistry Nankai University City, China Chemistry Certifications

Certified Project Management Professional (PMP) ~ ITIL Certified ~ Oracle Certified Professional (OCP) ~ Six Sigma Green Belt Certified ~

Beginning of Leadership (BEL) \sim Personal Leadership Strategy (PLS) \sim Leadership Development Course (LDC) \sim Change Acceleration Process (CAP) \sim Fundamental of Leadership (FoL) \sim

Languages

English & Chinese (fluent)

Skills

Architect, AUTOMOTIVE, backup, business solution, capacity planning, Chinese, closing, coaching, Data Warehouse, DBA, databases, database, Engineer, English, ERP, fast, Features, financial, Government, Hyperion, ITIL, LAN, Leadership, Leadership Development, Linux, Excel, Windows OS, PowerPoint, 2000, MS Word, migration, Network Design, network, Oracle 9, Oracle, Oracle 8i, Oracle Application, DB, Oracle Database, Oracle Designer 2000, PeopleSoft, PeopleTools I, PeopleTools II, Project Management, quality control, real-time, research, servers, Six Sigma, Strategy, switches, tax, user support, Transportation, treasury, troubleshooting, Unix, upgrading, Upgrade, Veritas, Visio, WAN